Andrea, I'm so glad you reached out to me and
Andrea 很高兴你联系了我
could come today, because I wanted to introduce you to Jessica.
并且今天能够过来 我想让你认识下 Jessica
She's a course developer at U'dasti and
她是优达学城的一名课程研发人员
she's going to helping us build your app idea.
她将帮助我们构想你的应用
&gt;&gt; Catherine's been telling me all about the app that you'd like to make to help
&gt;&gt; Catherine 告诉我你想要开发一款应用
people learn about the Miwok language.
帮助人们学习米沃克语
Could you tell us more about that idea?
你能再详细介绍下你的想法吗？
&gt;&gt; Sure, so
&gt;&gt; 没问题
my family's a part of the Northern Sierra Miwok tribe in California.
我们家族属于加利福利亚北部山脉米沃克部落
And the language isn't being passed down from generation to generation anymore.
米沃克语已经不再代代相传了
My great grandmother was the last to speak the language fluently.
我的曾祖母是最后一位能够流利说出米沃克语的家族成员
&gt;&gt; Wow, I'm sorry to hear that.
&gt;&gt; 哇 很遗憾听到这一消息
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so I'd like to preserve the language in the family.
&gt;&gt; 是的 我希望这一语言能够继续保留在我的家族文化中
So, I had an app idea that could teach my kids how to pronounce things like
所以 我希望有一款应用 可以教我的孩子们
numbers and colors and phrases.
用米沃克语说出简单的事物 例如数字 颜色和一些短语
&gt;&gt; Okay, so that seems pretty straightforward.
&gt;&gt; 恩 这一想法很简单明了
So, the app would just be a list of words and
这款应用要能够列出一系列的单词
each word could have an English and a Miwok translation.
每个单词都有英语和米沃克语翻译
That sounds reasonable for our student to build, right?
我们的学员应该能够构建这款应用 对吧
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's assuming that they've taken the Android for
&gt;&gt; 前提是他们已经跟着你和 Cornell 学习了
Beginners course with you and Cornell already, right?
Android 初学者课程
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So,
&gt;&gt; 是的
they should already know how to build a layout and
他们应该已经知道如何构建布局
how to make a simple but interactive app.
以及如何构建简单但能够互动的应用
&gt;&gt; All right, so, if the student
&gt;&gt; 如果观看这节课的学员
watching doesn't feel comfortable with those concepts.
不太熟悉这些概念
They should probably go back to that course, review those topics, and
他们可以回到该课程 复习下这些主题
then come back.
然后再回来
&gt;&gt; Yeah and then we'll be building the Miwok app together with them.
&gt;&gt; 恩 然后我们就可以和他们一起构建米沃克应用
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that sounds doable and you know,
&gt;&gt; 听起来是可行的
this app will teach the dialect of Miwok the tribe speaks.
这款应用是教大家如何说米沃克部落的方言
But our students can take this app and modify it to teach any language.
但是学员可以对应用做出修改 教大家说任何语言
&gt;&gt; That's so true, there are so
&gt;&gt; 完全是这样的
many different languages that could be preserved by this.
这样可以保留太多种类的语言了
It's amazing if we could help other cultures, but
如果能够帮助其他文化 那就太棒了
by the way, how long is this going to take?
顺便问下 需要多长时间？
&gt;&gt; Well, I'd estimate about four to six weeks,
&gt;&gt; 大概四到六周吧
if we work alongside the students and then they pace themselves out.
我们会和学员一起合作 然后他们自己去开发
That sounds reasonable, I can't wait to show the app to my family.
&gt;&gt; 听起来很合理 我迫不及待地想要向我的家人展示这款应用了
&gt;&gt; Yeah and another reason why I'm so excited about this app is,
&gt;&gt; 我对这款应用非常期待的另一个原因是
because our student may feel like a beginner.
我们的学员可能觉得自己是初学者
You might not be able to create something that useful.
不能创建非常有用的应用
But we're going to show them in this course, that with their current skill
但是我们将向他们展示 凭借目前所掌握的技能
set they can tackle real challenges in their community.
他们是可以为自己的社区解决实际难题的
&gt;&gt; Yeah that's right, such that preserving the local culture.
&gt;&gt; 对呢 例如保护当地文化
&gt;&gt; Exactly.
&gt;&gt; 是的
&gt;&gt; I completely agree but to be honest, I've never built an app before.
&gt;&gt; 我非常赞同 但说实话 我还从来没构建过应用
Where do we even start?
从哪开始啊？
&gt;&gt; That's okay.
&gt;&gt; 没关系
I actually have a really great idea.
我实际上有个非常好的想法
Let's ask our student for help.
我们向学员寻求帮助吧
&gt;&gt; All right. All right, so
&gt;&gt; 好的
if Andrea can provide us the vocabulary list.
如果 Andrea 能够提供词汇表
Why don't you help us brainstorm how we can present this information to a user
不妨你来帮助我们想想如何向应用用户
within an app.
展示这一信息吧
&gt;&gt; And take some time to think about this because a lot of people
&gt;&gt; 请花些时间认真思考下 很多人在将想法变成
struggle with translating an idea into an actual app.
实际的应用前都要努力思考一段时间
So, this will be good practice for you.
这将是一次很好的锻炼机会